## Charlie Van Norman

(650) 440 - 5445 charlie@vannorman.ai

#### **SUMMARY**

Generalist developer and project manager who designs, builds, and ships products; Former entrepreneur who strives for a frictionless and effective user experience

[ C#/.net, Python, Django, React, SQL, VR, AR, iOS, Android, Unity3D, CI/CD, Azure, AWS, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch ]

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **InContext Solutions**Sr. Software Engineer

Sr. Software Engineer Feb 2019 - present

Full stack software and game development for 3D virtual shopping / research platform

## **Radian Consulting**

Principal Aug 2017 - Feb 2019 Perceptiv Labs: Extended the Placenote SDK, to reduce onboarding time for 200+ platform developers by 80%

Extended Reality Labs: As interim CTO, led development of flagship VR enterprise training product and helped raise \$1.5M

Humon AI Company: Led the redesign of a VR controlled industrial robot interface, contributing to \$5M acquisition offer

TagIt Inc: Developed a 3D management application prototype to track items in real time in a chip manufacturing facility

3Scan Inc: Built a VR brain exploration game for Exploratorium brain science exhibit for Oculus / XBox

## Super Math World

Founder June 2013 - Aug 2017 Produced two immersive 3D math sandbox games for grades K-8. My contributions include:

- Designed and programmed game and map editor
- Built and maintained full web stack on AWS
- Led user growth reaching ~100,000 users (~25,000 paid)
- Managed 7 employees, interns and contractors

#### **Synapse School**

Technical Director Jan 2013 - May 2015 Designed and taught game programming and 3D design curriculum for grades K-8

## SELECTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Deep-Q Lunar Lander Trained an AI to achieve maximum score in a javascript based Programmer Lunar Lander game **Space Frog** A VR Active Game to explore the limits of room scale. Punch Programmer, designer rockets from your fists and dodge aliens to save the Frog Prince **Polymer Playground** March 2018 Designed programmatic animations for molecular machine concepts at the Foresight Atomic Precision conference **Magic Hands VR** Nov 2017 - Dec 2017 Built a VR game with portal travel and omnidirectional flight locomotion with Leap Motion to detect spell casting gestures

## **EDUCATION**

<b>Deep Learning Camp</b> San Francisco, CA	Oct 2018 - Dec 2018 Theory, math and Image segmentation (U-Net, Caps-net)
<b>Urban Land Institute</b> San Francisco, CA	Aug - Sep 2010 Real Estate Development Certificate
<b>Cal Poly Polytechnic</b> Pomona, CA	Sep 2001 - May 2007 B.S. International Business + ME and CS coursework

## **AWARDS**

<b>BR4IN.io Hackathon</b> Honolulu, HI, 2018	Second prize winner - built Breath Force, a VR + EEG app to detect calm brain states and give magic power
<b>VR Wellness Summit</b> SF, CA, 2018	Most Innovative Idea - Whisper Castle, an asynchronous multiplayer audio message exchange platform in VR
Shark Tank Pitch SF, CA, 2014	First prize winner - pitched Mathbreakers to an audience of $\sim\!200$ and a panel of 7 angel investors
IndieGoGo Game Jam SF, CA, 2013	First prize winner - built Ring Flight, a flying game controlled by leaning, using a Kinect to detect body position
<b>Maker Faire</b> San Mateo, CA, 2011	Editor's Choice Award & Kid's Choice Award - for Code Hero, a javascript learning video game